Finding Aid for the Freolac Club Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Freolac Club Collection
1968-2006
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0158
0.42 linear_feet
Biography/History
The Freolac Club was organized in 1916 to bring together men of culture, having diverse interests and professions, who were concerned with keeping alive their quest for knowledge and truth in many fields of intellectual interest. Meetings are held once a month during the months of October to December and February to June. Members present papers on a topic of interest to them. Until 1981, members attending the meeting would provide critical feedback on papers presented. After this date, this practice was discontinued.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, meeting announcements, newspaper clippings, biographical material, program schedules, reports, rosters of members, copies of delivered speeches, lecture notes for presentations, and miscellaneous material. Dates of the material range from 1968 to 2006.
- Biographical Material
  - Baker, William Robert
  - Crabb, Alfred Leland
  - DeWitt, John Hibbett
  - Gleaves, Edwin S.
  - Higgins, Thomas Aquinas
  - Koch, Jeffrey M.
  - Miles, Roy A., Jr.
  - Miles, Roy A., Sr.
  - Shriver, Thomas A.
- Committee Reports
  - Committee on Membership, March 2, 1981
- Correspondence
  - 1969
  - 1970-1979
  - 1980-1988
- Financial Statements
  - 1998
- Mailing Lists
  - Undated list
- Meeting Announcements
  - 1969
  - 1970-1975
  - 1976-1979
  - 1980-1981
- Membership Rosters
  - Club Roster, 1981-1982
  - Club Roster, undated
- Miscellaneous
  - Notes, undated
- Program Schedules
  - 1968-2003
- Speeches and Lecture Notes
  - Adams, Dillard G. “The Story of Fort Harker.”, May 5, 2003 (Folder 1)
  - Aden, John. “Edmund Burke and the Conservative Idea.”, May 1, 1978. (lecture notes) (Folder 2)
  - Brown, Neill S. “Reminiscing.” Undated. (Folder 3)
  - Buck, J. Orton. “Captain Joseph Brant – Mohawk Name: Thayendanegea.”, June 3, 1985 (Folder 4)
  - Crabb, Alfred Leland. “Your Great-Grandparents Were There.”, April 8, 1974 (Folder 5)
  - Gabhart, Herbert C. “Numerology and the Number 7.”, February 5, 1979 (Folder 6)
  - Gabhart, Herbert C. “Useful Old Proverbs.”, 1984 (Folder 7)
  - Gleaves, Edwin S. “The Future of Books and Libraries in an Age of Hyperlinks.”, May 7, 2001 (Folder 8)
  - Gray, David. “In-House Counsel: A Change of Perspective.”, December 3, 1990 (Folder 9)
  - Hoobler, James A. “Yakub Beg: The Emir of Kashgaria, 1872-1878.”, February 4, 1980. (lecture notes) (Folder 10)
  - Koch, Jeffrey M. “The Battle of Bushy Run.”, September 2001 (Folder 11)
  - Koch, Jeffrey M. “FREOLAC: A Presentation of Our Collected History.”, April 8, 2003 (Folder 12)
  - Koch, Jeffrey M. “Huzzah for the Whiskey Boys.”, February 1999 (Folder 13)
  - Koch, Jeffrey M. “Meagher of the Sword: The Life of Thomas F. Meagher – Revolutionary, Lawyer, General, Governor.”, December 1, 2003 (Folder 14)
  - Koch, Jeffrey M. “Steel Titan: The Life of Charles M. Schwab.”, March 1977 (Folder 15)
  - Manchester, Paul. “Félix Lope de Vega y Carpio, 1562-1635.”, December 4, 1972. (lecture notes) (Folder 16)
  - Miles, Roy A., Jr. “Fifteen Miles from Nowhere: Lascassas, Tennessee.” Undated. (Folder 17)
  - Miles, Roy A., Jr. “A Glimpse into the Universe.”, October 2002 (Folder 18)
  - Miles, Roy A., Jr. “The Maquis.”, November 1993 (Folder 19)
  - Miles, Roy A., Jr. “Thoroughbreds.”, June 3, 1991 (Folder 20)
  - Neese, Charles G. “Ana.”, November 2, 1987 (Folder 21)
  - Rainey, Bill. [“The Affair of Spring Hill.”], February 2, 2004 (Folder 22)
  - Rosenberg, Fred. “Melungeons.”, May 4, 1992 (Folder 23)
  - Rosenberg, Joseph F. “Family History.”, April 3, 2003 (Folder 24)
  - Rosenberg, Joseph F. “The Ring.”, October 6, 2003 (Folder 25)
  - Shriver, Thomas H. “Lift Up Your Eyes to Wonder: A Layman Looks at the Universe.”, October 7, 1974 (Folder 26)
  - Sitton, W. B. “A Freeman’s Song.”, (poem) Fall 2000 (Folder 27)
- Recorded Speeches on Audio Cassette
  - Tape 1: Side 1 (Folder 1)
    Valentine, Andy. “Everything That Rises Must Converge: Extraordinary Delusion and the Madness of Crowds.” Delivered June 6, 2005.
  - Tape 1: Side 2 (Folder 2)
    Wade, Henry, III. “A Plague is Upon Us: The Black Plague of 1347 and Its Effects on Society.” Delivered September 6, 2005.
  - Tape 2: Side 1 (Folder 3)
    Sullivan, Walter L. “William Faulkner Joins the Air Force, or Why Writers Lie.” Delivered November 7, 2005.
  - Tape 2: Side 2 (Folder 4)
    Cantrell, Ben. “A Primer on Federal-State Relations.” Delivered February 2, 2006.
  - Tape 3: (Folder 5)
    McClanahan, Larry. “DNA Genealogy.” Delivered March 6, 2006.